## Daniel A. Pinedo

### Human Resources Strategy & Research

**\** 213.999.5619

@ daniel.pinedo@cgu.edu

% pinedo.org

#### **SUMMARY**

Evidence-based Human Resource strategist specialized in management of adaptive and creative organizational change. Passionate about sustaining diverse and inclusive cultures that nurture individual differences leading to high performing and happy knowledge workers. Strong background using technical tools alongside organizational behavior and management research and evaluation methodologies.

#### **ABILITIES**



**HR Strategy** 



**HR Research & Development** 



**Diversity & Inclusion** 



**Organizational Transformation** 



**Performance Monitoring & Evaluation** 



**Talent Management** 

### **EDUCATION**

### MA Psychology in Organizational Behavior & Evaluation

**Claremont Graduate University** 

GPA **3.5** / 4.0

### MA Clinical Psychology

**Sofia University** 

BA

**Naropa University** 

### **COURSEWORK**

Organizational Behavior	Organizational Culture	Research Methods
Intermediate Statistics	ANOVA	Multiple Regression
Categorical Data Analysis	Network Analysis	Foundations of Evaluation

**Comparative Evaluation Theory** 

#### **TECHNOLOGIES**

#### **Programming**

R SPSS C++ Python LaTeX

### **PROJECTS**

#### ICM Partners, HR department

## 09/2018 - Ongoing

Part of a course-based project for one of the largest creative talent agencies in the world. CHRO has grown the HR organization from under 10 employees to a strategic asset with an entire floor of employees in under a year.

- 150 + employees participated in organizational diagnosis of assistant agent job design and agent leadership development that provided insights into specific discrepancies in how agents and assistants give and receive job feedback.
- · 1-year development plan presented, approved, and entire team will be continuing project on contract at course end.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Research Associate

#### Accenture PLC, Talent Innovation Lab

## 11/2018 - Current

Member of Research and Development Lab for strategy and decision-making within selection and training for global consulting firm. Job functions include: statistical and qualitative analysis, literature review, and research design.

 Member of two projects with potential reach and impact for selection of each job position within Accenture as a global company with 475,000 employees.

#### Lecturer

#### **Mount Saint Mary's University**

**1** 01/2016 - 05/2018

% msmu.edu

Undergraduate contract faculty position in psychology department. This role included teaching, academic counseling, and administration.

- Taught upper division courses for five continuous semesters, including: Research Methods Lecture and Lab (two courses; SP16, FA16, SP17, FA17 2 sections each, SP18), Social Psychology (SP17), Organizational Psychology (FA17), Positive Psychology (syllabus designed, course not taught).
- Academic counseling for 15 students on an ongoing basis including: tracking graduation requirements, course selection, career counseling, monitoring degree progress, and crisis counseling.

### Clinical Psychologist Intern

#### **Sovereign Health Group**

**1** 08/2014 - 08/2015

Inpatient dual-diagnosis (mental illness and addictions) facility that provided individual and group therapy, psychological assessment, and organizational consulting services.

- · Consistently maintained caseload of ten or more clients, and maintained insurance billing and review.
- Assisted program director in streamlining management of distribution of caseload to employees, leading to 25% increase in overall
  revenue by increasing cases per employee, and increasing insurance billing overall.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Manager / Interim Director

#### Sofia University Electroencephalography Lab

**1** 09/2012 - 06/2013

% sofia.edu

Electrophysiology lab for psychology graduate school specialized in physiological correlates of meditative states, event-related potentials, and brainwave analysis.

- created training program for graduate students with four paid positions for students in using EEG equipment and running experiments with human subjects.
- consulted three faculty members in the research methodologies used in EEG analysis, researched potential grants, and reported updates
  of research weekly to the office of the provost.

#### Teaching Assistant

#### Institute of Transpersonal Psychology (Sofia University)

**1** 09/2011 - 12/2012

% sofia.edu

Teaching assistant to Dr. Arthur Hastings, faculty of research methods for PhD psychology program.

 Graded papers, co-taught, and provided office hours for assistance to doctoral students in Doctoral Research Seminar (FA11-12), and Doctoral Thesis Seminar (SP12)

### **Network Operations Engineer**

#### **Oversee**

**10/2007 - 08/2008** 

% oversee.net

Night shift network operations for website portfolio company. Role was mission critical as network infrastructure was primary revenue generation avenue of company.

- · Had 100% compliance rate of service level agreements between my desk and all internal clients throughout my tenure.
- Oversaw 2 catastrophic network outages due to systems deployment errors and ensured mitigation of downtime to under 10 minutes in both cases, including physical access to co-located network infrastructure.

### **Network Operations Supervisor**

#### **CalPOP**

**11/2007 11/2007** 

Co-location internet service provider located in a telecommunications hub in downtown Los Angeles.

 Supervised 15 direct report staff in scheduling, project management for network and systems administrators, and management of deployment and continuous maintenance of over 5,000 servers and IP addresses.

### **PUBLICATIONS**

# Mindfulness training as an intervention for substance user incarcerated adolescents: A pilot grounded theory study.

#### **Substance Use & Misuse**

Himelstein, S., Saul, S., Garcia-Romeu, A., & Pinedo, D.

## 2014 % DOI: 10.3109/10826084.2013.852580

The study investigated how to effectively teach mindfulness to 10 incarcerated adolescent substance users (N = 10) in an urban California detention setting. A grounded theory approach was used to collect and analyze interview data over a 1-year period during 2011 and 2012 in order to develop an initial theory for teaching mindfulness to incarcerated adolescent substance users.